## **Kelly Dunn**

#### General

I am a Professional Software Engineer with a decade of experience in various industries, including Education, Gaming, Music, IOT, Marketing, and Finance. I am Technical Leader focusing on Distributed Systems, Site Reliability, and Scalaiblity. I thrive in problem spaces that require heightened collaboration, cross-fuctional coordination, and quality of life in the workplace.

# Professional Experience

#### **Splice**

Sr. Software Engineer // Technical Lead - Search + SRE October 2018 - Present

- Improved p99 Search Latencies 100x to sub 100ms responses. Lead and oversaw an initiative to migrate legacy search infrastructure to a more modern and managed alterantive. Productionalized an experimental ML feature in ElasticSearch.
- Built a CI/CD Pipeline with AWS Codebuild that was 30x cheaper and was 12x faster than a home-grown solution.

Technologies: Go, MySQL, ElasticSearch, Docker, Terraform, SQS, Redis, ECS, Fargate, Codebuild, Datadog, BigQuery

#### **Simple**

Sr. Software Engineer // Technical Lead - SRE + Platform July 2015 - August 2018

- Improved Mean Time to Recovery by 50%, and decreased the number of Outages per day by 60% in six months.
- Upgraded applications, CI/CD, and monitoring systems to Kubernetes workloads. Reduced infrastructure costs by 8x, and deployment times 3x.

Technologies: Ruby, Go, Java, Scala, Kafka, PostgreSQL, SQS, DynamoDB, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, Datadog

#### Simply Measured

Software Engineer - Product / Data October 2013 - June 2015

- Created Map Reduce jobs that normalized billions of rows of Facebook and Youtube data.
- · Identified and fixed memory leaks in mission critical worker processes.
- Created supporting web services that decoupled SimplyMeasured's web product from the Salesforce CRM.

Technologies: Ruby, Go, Java, RabbitMQ, MySQL, HBase, Memcache

#### **Sifteo**

Software Engineer December 2011 - July 2013

- Created an online Game Marketplace, which serviced tens of thousands of Sifteo Game purchases and downloads.
- Created an Auditing Service, which collected Quality Assurance data on over 300,000 Sifteo Products created overseas.

Technologies: Ruby, Javascript, C++, C#, PostgreSQL, Redis

### **Software Contracting and Software Education**

Software Engineer August 2008-December 2011

- Built web services for clients as a Software Engineer at Originate
- · Created web services that enabled musicians to distribute their music as a Software Engineer at Kelly Dunn LLC
- Taught fundamentals of Computer Science such as Data Structures, Algorithms, Databases, and Web Development at University of Washington

Technologies: Ruby, Java, Javascript, C, C++, MySQL, Chef, AWS

#### Certification



#### Education